擎天柱！
Prime!
你们的人到底在搞啥名堂？
What in blazes are your people doing out here?!
我们可是有协议的 不许伤及无辜
We had an agreement. "No collateral damage".
很抱歉 福勒探员 可我担保全体汽车人都在这里
I am sorry, Agent Fowler. But all Autobots are present and accounted for.
那这又是怎么回事 距奥马哈市20英里的地方 两个傻大个儿正打得不可开交
Then explain why I'm receiving reports of two jumbo-size bots mixing it up twenty miles outside Omaha?
霸天虎？
Decepticons?
他们最近起了内讧 看来威震天的队伍也不好带了
There's has been plenty of infighting lately. Megatron can't seem to keep his ranks in line.
我刚好赶到 给你们看看
Well, I'm just arriving on the scene. Have a look.
我搞不懂 抛开涂装不说 那家伙不可能是天震
I don't know. Paintjob aside, it can't be Skyquake.
你和擎天柱不是把他干掉了么？
You and Optimus pounded him into the ground.
后来红蜘蛛把他弄活了 只不过成了一只僵尸
Before Starscream yanked him back out. As some kind of undead terrorcon.
还有个问题 跟他互掐的人又是谁？
The question still stands: who is the dance partner?
火种源在上 是我们的人！
By the Allspark! It is one of ours!
千斤顶！
Wheeljack!
哈哈 老千回来了！
Ha-ha, Jackie's back!!
就算亚伯拉罕・林肯回来了又怎样
I don't care if Abraham Lincoln's back!
得想办法控制局势 否则我们全都会上11点的新闻！
We have to contain the situation before we all wind up on the eleven o'clock news!
你无路可逃了 虎子！
You've got nowhere left to run, Con!
这里是福勒探员 在…
This is special agent Fowler of --
哇！冷静点 愣头青！我跟你是一伙的！
whoa! Stand down, hot-head! I'm on your side!
就知道他们要来凑热闹
Had a feeling the gang might show.
老千！
Jackie!
就它了
That will do.
啊！又是这套把戏！
Ah! Not this again!
别想跑
Oh no you don't!
千斤顶！
Wheeljack!
老千！别！
Jackie! No!
骇翼把这个地方给炸飞了
Dreadwing rigged the place to blow.
骇翼？
Dreadwing?
其实这是你的杰作吧 猛男
Actually, it was your handiwork, sparky.
这里是一个加油站
It's called a gas station.
类似于能量补给站 不能在这里进行交火
Kinda like an energon depot. Doesn't mix well with blaster fire.
哼 那只虎子逃掉了
Huh. Well, our Con is getting away.
千斤顶 在这个星球上
Wheeljack. There are other considerations.
需要注意的地方还有很多
While upon this world
你最好服从我的指挥
you would do well to follow my lead.
噢！轻点 医生
Ow! Take it easy, Doc.
这条胳膊我还要呢
I need that arm.
想要的话就别乱动
Hold still and maybe you'll keep it.
我说 指挥官
Look, Commander.
很抱歉我放了一只大号烟花 我保证不会再犯了
Apologies for fireworks. Won't happen again.
不过 我已经跟踪骇翼有上百光年了
But I've tracked Dreadwing across a hundred light-years of space!
我以为你在银河系流浪
I thought you were roving the Galaxy...
是为了…
You know...
搜寻汽车人的幸存者
looking for Autobot refugees?
我就是那么做的 然后我找到了一个
I was. Until I found one...
雷霆救援队员
A Wrecker.
谁？
Who?!
浪花
... Seaspray.
哈！那个老家伙怎么样了？
Ha! ... How is old Barnacle Butt?
不怎么样 小隔 其实他已经粉身碎骨了
Not so good, Bulk. Blown to bits, actually.
什么？不会吧…
What? No...
骇翼…
Dreadwing.
（Jackhammer 钻击号 本意是手提钻 \NG1元祖漫画中是纽约市一个摔跤手的名字)
My flier, the "Jackhammer"
收到了几光年外 由浪花发自德雷昂的信号
picked up Seaspray's signal a couple of light-years from Maderan.
我们彼此联络之后 约定了见面地点在多米顿星系
We made contact and arranged a rendezvous in the Dromedon system.
但是骇翼肯定是截获了通信
But Dreadwing must have intercepted the transmission.
因为他先对浪花下了手
'cause he got to Seaspray first.
一颗感应雷
Proximity bomb.
想把我们两个同时干掉
Supposed to take us both out.
我应该庆幸钻击号足够结实
Guess I should be glad that Jackhammer can take a punch.
我发现了骇翼的离子尾迹 为了逮住他 我足足追击了十几个星系
I picked up the Dreadwing's ion trail and tracked it through a dozen solar systems before catching up with him.
而他正好将我带回到这颗蓝宝石
And he led me right back to this marble.
宇宙真小啊 嗯…
Some coincidence, huh.
我了解骇翼
I know of this Dreadwing.
他是追踪者部队的指挥官
He was Captain of a Seeker armada.
和他的孪生兄弟天震一样
And as such -- like his twin Skyquake
都是霸天虎事业的忠实狂热分子
-- fiercely loyal to the Decepticon cause.
毫无疑问 骇翼是奔地球来的 为了向他唯一真正的主人效忠
Dreadwing has no doubt travelled to Earth to pay allegiance to his one true master...
祝他观光愉快
Hope he's enjoying the visit.
这里将会是他旅途的终点
It's gonna be his last.
千斤顶
Wheeljack!
这颗星球大部分地区都居住着智慧生命体
This planet is heavily inhabited.
任何对霸天虎的军事打击都要慎重考虑
Any strike we make against the Decepticons must be carefully measured
作为一个团队 我们不能冒危及人类的危险
as a team, lest we risk endangering the human population.
那你是建议我们在这里坐以待毙？
Are you suggesting we sit back and do nothing?
你 这个桀骜不驯的家伙
You! Loose cannon!
你的莽撞行为差点暴露了我们
Your cowboy antics almost blew our cover!
- 暴露？\N- 我们在地球上得伪装起来 老千
- Cover?\N- We're robots in disguise, Jackie.
在基地外 你需要一个地球上的车辆形态
You needed an Earth-based vehicle mode outside of here.
你打下的那艘太空船
That spaceship you shot down.
可不是地球款式的
Not Earth-based!
我费了很大劲才把那架飞行器清理干净
I had to jump through some big hoops to get it hauled out of plain sight.
你得把你的人看紧点 擎天柱
You need to keep a tighter leash on your people, Prime!
看紧点？
A tighter leash?
我得说个明白 小东西
Let me clarify, tiny.
老千…
Jackie!
我不是给擎天柱打下手的
I'm not one of Optimus Prime's people.
我去和他谈一谈
I'll talk to him. Err...
如果你允许的话
with your permission.
当然可以
Of course.
看来 这个新来的有些蔑视权威
So. The new guy has a little problem with authority.
千斤顶和隔板曾在雷霆救援队中共事
Wheeljack and Bulkhead served together in the Wreckers.
那是一支独立于常规指挥体系的部队
A combat unit that operated outside the normal chain of command.
哦 兵痞子
Hm. Black ops.
他们执行的任务通常无人愿意接手\N而他们当中的很多人都已殒命沙场
They accepted missions no one else would.\NAnd many of them did not come back.
威震天陛下
Lord Megatron.
我誓死效忠于您
I live to serve.
平身 骇翼
Rise, Dreadwing.
你们兄弟二人的忠诚无人可及
Loyalty such as yours is a rare commodity.
我的忠诚发自于内心
Mine runs deep and true.
当然 驱使我前来这里的不仅仅是忠诚
Yet it is not loyalty alone brought me here.
嗯？
Oh?
我是来确认我尊兄的死的
I seek confirmation of the demise of one whom I considered a brother.
你怎么知道他阵亡了？
How did you learn of his passing?
我们孪生兄弟共享着一个分离的火种
My twin and I shared a split-Spark.
因此两个人的身体结构完全相同
Our metal are but two halves of the same life-force.
即使我和他相隔着一个银河系\N我也能感受到他在这行星上的一举一动
Even across the Galaxy I sensed when he emerged from stasis on this planet.
他的火种已不复…
And when his Spark was no more.
的确
It is true.
天震死于汽车人之手
Skyquake perished at the hands of the Autobots.
虽然这不是我的责任
Though not, in fact, under my watch.
所以 作为回报
Then by the Pit
这颗该死星球上的所有汽车人 都要给他陪葬
every last Autobot on this accursed world will pay.
当时机成熟时 汽车人会为他们所犯下的罪行付出代价
The Autobots WILL be punished for their crime and many others how and when I see fit.
但是主人！
But Master!
争辩只会扰乱计划 带来失败！
Conflicting agendas will only result in chaos. And failure.
你最好记住 骇翼
You would be wise to remember that, Dreadwing.
你现在是在我手下办事
You are under my command now, and as such,
必须服从我的指挥
you must follow my lead.
老千 你看
Jacky. Look.
如果没有人类的帮助
Even if it weren't for the humans
我们是无法与虎子们相抗衡的
we couldn't take on the Cons right now.
敌众我寡
We're outnumbered.
路霸 烈火 撞针 旋暴 浪花…
Roadbuster, Pyro, Impactor, Rotorstorm, Seaspray...
他们都死了！
all dust.
那正是我想说的
That's what I'm talking about.
无论是雷霆救援队还是汽车人
Wreckers are Autobots.
都已所剩无几
There just aren't that many of us left.
不过在擎天柱的领导下
But if we get behind Optimus
我们有机会结束这一切 彻底结束
we have a chance to end this. Once and for all.
像擎天柱这样的人 都是嘴上说的好听
Guys like Optimus, they talk a good game
一旦你成了一堆废铁 他们甚至不愿弄脏他们的手
but when you're in the scrap they don't want to get their hands dirty.
哇哦 哇哦 哇哦
Whoa-whoa-whoa.
你不像我这般了解擎天柱
You don't know Optimus like I do.
我曾认为雷霆救援队员的身份是我的一切
Being a Wrecker meant everything to me
但我最终想通了
but I left that behind--
因为领袖才是最实在的 接着忽悠
-- because Prime was the real thing, blah-blah-blah.
千斤顶 我知道你听得到 我有一个提议
Wheeljack. I know you are out there, listening. I have  a proposition for you.
那是谁？
Is that?
骇翼！
Dreadwing.
如果你有火种的话 到这个坐标处见我
Meet me at these coordinates. If you have the Spark.
我这就去见你 虎子 只为去看你被电得外焦里嫩
I'll see you there, Con. Just to watch you fry.
老千 这是个陷阱！
Jacky, it's a trap.
我知道 是陷阱又怎么样？
I know. But when has that ever stopped me?
你一起来吗？
You coming with?
至少让我去叫后援
At least let me call for backup.
你知道的 雷霆救援队从来不叫后援
You know Wreckers don't call for backup--
他们只叫人清理敌骸
- They call for clean up!\N- They call for clean up!
我真没想到你会来
I wasn't certain you'd come.
我做事不喜欢半途而废
I don't like unfinished business.
就这点儿能耐？
That all you've got?
如果你想从这里飞出去
If you're thinking about flying out of here...
那可打错主意了！
Think again.
隔板！
Bulkhead!
隔板的信号显示他离这里有一千公里远
Bulkhead's signal. Over a thousand miles from here.
我估计千斤顶和他在一起
And I would have to imagine that Wheeljack is with him.
你试过联系他吗？
Have you attempted contact?
没有回应
No response.
怎么这么慢 小隔？
What took you so long, Bulk?
别告诉我跟了擎天柱之后让你…
Don't tell me riding with Prime has made you...
变弱了？
... soft?
你听不听我的指挥是一回事
If you will not take orders from me, that is one thing.
但如果你让我手下的汽车人身处险境…
But when you place one of my Autobots in danger...
恕我直言 长官 隔板很清楚这其中的风险
With all due respect, sir, Bulkhead knew the risks.
每名救援队员都有这觉悟
Every Wrecker does.
我肯定他就在这堆石头下面
And I'm sure he's just somewhere in this rubble.
擎天柱 隔板的信号已经不在你现在的位置了
Optimus! Bulkhead's signal has moved from your current position.
你要一起来吗？
You coming with?
你和隔板是老相识了 你却喜欢只身独行
You and Bulkhead share quite a history. And yet you prefer to work alone.
雷霆救援队很久以前就失散了
The Wreckers scattered a long time ago.
并且单独行动更有效率
And alone is usually a lot less complicated.
我们离居民区很近 要记住…
We are close to population. Remember.
不能朝汽油开火
Blasters and fuel pumps don't mix.
我们的大男孩就在前面
Our boy is just up ahead.
嘿 伙计们
Hey, guys.
见鬼…
... Scrap.
这次你真要把自己变成一堆废渣了 伙计！
You really got yourself in a heap of scrap this time, partner.
离远点 老千
Stay back, Jackie!
最好赶快进行拆除
Better get to work.
你以前拆过炸弹吗？
Have you defused one of these before?
双保险 假铅芯 各种陷阱… 简直是艺术品
Failsafes... dummy leads... booby traps. It's a work of art.
骇翼 你在哪里？
Dreadwing. Where are you?
做我应做的事情 威震天陛下
Merely pursuing my destiny, Lord Megatron.
我不是命令过你不要轻举妄动吗？
Did I not order you to stand down?
请原谅我 尊敬的陛下
Forgive me, one true Master.
但愿在我击败擎天柱后 您能认可我
But it is my hope that vanquishing Optimus Prime will earn your respect.
擎天柱没那么容易对付
Optimus is not so easily disposed of.
我已经跟无数愚蠢的自大狂说过这话了！
As I keep trying to explain to all of those who foolishly attempt it.
老千 如果你还不放手的话 我们就都完了
Jackie. If you don't abort, we're both gonna need clean up!
别让我分心 小隔
Trying to focus here, Bulk.
擎天柱哪里去了？
Where's Optimus?
哼 就像我告诉你的
It's like I told you.
当我们拖后腿的时候 头头们总是置身事外
When the scrap hits the fan blades -- the generals are the first to bail.
不 擎天柱不是这样的人
No. Not Optimus.
我向您保证 主人\N擎天柱和他的两个同伙会被轰成原子
I assure you, Master. In but a few moments Optimus and two others wili be blown to atoms.
我批准你的行动 骇翼
I will allow it, Dreadwing.
这也是为了缅怀你的孪生兄弟 但下不为例
In memory of your departed twin. But only this once.
要是骇翼能活着回来 我都会觉得吃惊
I will be quite surprised if we ever set eyes upon Dreadwing again.
擎天柱在哪里？
... Where's the Prime?
骇翼？如果你真与天震是孪生兄弟
Dreadwing! If you are anything like Skyquake, I know that you value loyalty and honour.
说这些有意义吗 擎天柱？
Is there a point to your bluster, Prime?
因为威震天丝毫不懂这些
Only that Megatron knows nothing of those principles.
他活着只为了毁灭与征服
He lives only for destruction and conquest.
而你有另一个选择 解除炸弹！
But there is another path. Deactivate the bomb.
赶紧离开这里！
Get out of here already!
既然我没把你丢在桑德坎 也不会把你留在这里
I didn't leave you on Sandocan and I'm not leaving you here.
面对现实吧 我们中只有一人能拆除炸弹 而那人就是骇翼
Face it. There's only one bot who can defuse this mess, and his name is Dreadwing.
炮火越来越近了 好像指挥官他…哦！
Blaster fire is getting closer. As if the Commander...
抱歉了 老千 这是因为我爱你！
Sorry, Jackie. It’s ‘cause I love you.
对不起了 鱼儿们
Oh, sorry, fishies!
隔板 等等！
Bulkhead! Wait!
别挡道！
Out of my way!
你给我听着 小隔！
Will you listen to me, Bulk?
你是对的 骇翼是唯一一个能拆除炸弹的家伙
You were right. Dreadwing is the only one who can defuse it.
擎天柱也明白这点
And Optimus knows it too.
骇翼？拆除炸弹 否则你将自食其果
Dreadwing, defuse the bomb. Or fall victim to your own device!
能为我的兄弟报仇 我很荣幸
I will gladly sacrifice myself to avenge my brother.
那反过来 我们也将为兄弟报仇从而一起光荣地回归火种源
Then we will in turn gladly join the Allspark with our brother.
你…是不可能动摇我们的
And with you. You'll never shake us.
好吧…
Very well.
其实我知道要么是蓝色 要么是黄色… 要么是红色
I had it narrowed down to the blue or the yellow. Or the red.
那么 叫谁来收场呢？
So. Who do we call for cleanup?
擎天柱还活着
Optimus Prime still lives.
骇翼 你也活着
As do you, Dreadwing.
虽然微不足道 但好歹算是个胜利
And that is a victory, however small.
相比天震的悲剧收场而言
As Skyquake so tragically discovered.
别再提起我的孪生兄弟 威震天陛下
Speak to me not of my twin, Lord Megatron.
我来到地球只为遵从您的意愿 别无二心
For I am here on Earth to obey your will. And yours alone.
指挥官 我只想说很荣幸见识了您的身手
Listen, Commander. I just wanna say... it was an honour watching you work.
我 嗯 我想我以前也许看错您了
I, uh, think maybe I had the wrong idea about you.
很显然比起单打独斗 你在团队中更能一展拳脚
And it would seem that you place a greater value on community than you otherwise let on.
喔 先别操之过急
Whoa, let's not jump the gun here.
得了老千 就算你离开了也会回来的
Come on, Jackie. If you leave, you'll probably just wind up coming right back again.
那只会浪费燃料 现在能量可是很短缺的
All that wasted fuel. And Energon is in short supply.
话说回来 我们这儿房间确实不多
Then again, we do have limited space.
我还不确定是否做好了放弃自由的准备
Not sure if I'm ready to give up my freedom just yet.
让我去探索一番 看看这颗大石头是否适合我
Maybe I could do some exploring, see if this rock suits me.
我并非嫌弃钻击号 不过你需要一个地球的车辆形态
No offense to the "Jackhammer", but you need an earth-based vehicle mode.